本视频由Brilliant赞助
1961年4月12日 尤里·加加林成为第一个进入太空的人
On the 12th of April 1961, Yuri Gagarin became the first ever human to venture into space.
他在那一天看到了全人类从未看见过的景象
On that day, he saw the world in a way that no human had ever seen before.
从那以后 只有560人进入过太空
Since then, just 560 people have been into space,
其中绝大多数人都经历了数年的训练才成为了宇航员
most of them being trained astronauts that spent years preparing for their flights.
可我们这些普通人什么时候能有机会去太空呢？
But when will the rest of us get a chance to visit space?
去了太空 我们又能干嘛呢？
And what will we do when we get there?
本期视频 我们将了解太空旅行的未来
In this video, we're going to look at the future of space tourism.
我们还将了解曾经自费去太空旅行的“宇航员”们
We're also going to look at the private astronauts that have paid to go into space
以及可复用火箭将如何重新开辟太空旅游业的市场
and how reusable rockets could help to kickstart the space tourism industry.
纵观人类航天史 总共只有7人曾花钱去过太空
Since the beginning of spaceflight, only 7 people have paid to go to space.
2001年 美国企业家Dennis Tito花2000万美元进行了8天的国际空间站之旅
In 2001, American entrepreneur Dennis Tito paid $20 million for an 8-day trip to the International Space Station.
当时 NASA觉得让游客去太空还不太合适 所以拒绝训练他
At the time, NASA thought it was inappropriate for tourists to go to space, so they refused to train him.
所以他和俄罗斯进行合作 与两名俄罗斯宇航员在联盟TM32任务中前往太空
Instead, he partnered with the Russian's and took a ride on Soyuz mission TM32 along with two Cosmonauts.
他回忆说第一次看到窗外时壮观的瞬间
He recalls the spectacular moment when he looked out of his window for the first time
看到了地球边缘的弧线在茫茫黑暗太空中的景象
and saw the curvature of the Earth against the darkness of space.
Dennis在空间站总共呆了八天 进行了一系列的实验
Dennis spent a total of 8 days on the ISS where he performed various experiments
并欣赏了地球的壮丽景色
and admired the incredible view of Earth.
迄今为止 自费前往太空的人都屈指可数
So far, the amount of paying visitors to space has been very low,
但这一切都将在不远的将来发生改变
but all that could change in the near future.
因为越来越多的私人航天公司研发了可复用火箭
With multiple private space companies developing reusable spacecraft,
太空飞行的成本骤降
the cost of spaceflight is starting to lower dramatically.
蓝色起源开发的新薛帕德飞船就是专门用来进行太空旅行的
Blue Origin are developing their "New Shepard" spacecraft specifically for tourism flights into space.
飞船有六个座位 拥有所有飞船中最大的窗户
This capsule has 6 seats with the largest windows ever seen in a spacecraft.
飞行中 火箭将加速升空至100公里的高空
During these flights, the rocket will accelerate up to 100km in altitude
之后关闭发动机 船箭分离
before cutting off the engine and releasing the capsule.
之后 飞船会进入自由落体状态 不过仍然在靠惯性飞往最高点
At this point, the capsule is essentially in free fall but still travelling upwards to its highest point.
此时飞船内的乘客就可以离开座位 体验失重的感觉了
Passengers inside the capsule will be able to leave their seats and experience the effects of weightlessness.
几分钟后 乘客将回到座位上
A few minutes later, the passengers will return to their seats
然后飞船再入大气 失重的体验就会慢慢消失
before the capsule enters the atmosphere and the effects of weightlessness disappear.
尽管飞行过程非常短
Although these flights will be extremely short,
但火箭的可复用性可以给客户们一次太空旅行的体验
the reusability of this rocket could give customers a chance to experience the wonders of space
价格却只要20万美元
from a price as low as $200,000.
尽管这仍然需要你家里有矿
Although this will still only satisfy the super rich,
但这还是让太空飞行向民航客机的价格和安全标准靠拢迈出了正确重要的一步
it's a step in the right direction if spaceflight is to ever achieve the price and safety standards of airliners.
而随着行业的进步 私人火箭公司们逐渐完善低成本太空旅行技术后
But as the industry grows and companies compete to develop the cheapest ride into space,
价格就会降得更低
these prices could fall even more.
如果所有飞船都能在大修前飞很多次
If each space vehicle can be reused multiple times before needing serious refurbishment,
那客户只要为乘员和燃料买单即可
the customer will only need to cover the cost of crew and fuel.
民航客机一天可以飞好几次
An airplane can fly multiple times per day,
寿命内可以飞上万次
and conduct tens of thousands of flights over its lifetime.
如果火箭能做到其十分之一
If a rocket can reach even a fraction of those numbers,
那太空旅行就能面向更多平凡大众
space tourism could be opened up to the wider public.
但研发低成本航天技术只解决了一半的问题
But developing a cheap ride into space is only half of the problem.
在太空维生的成本仍然高的吓人
The cost of actually living in space is still an incredibly expensive luxury.
NASA每年要花40亿美元维持国际空间站的运营
In order to run the International Space Station it costs NASA around $4 Billion each year.
在多年的反商业化后 NASA最近还是向自费客户说了句真香
After years of avoiding commercialization, NASA recently opened up the ISS to paying customers.
但由于极高的运营成本 国际空间站仍然还是富豪的旅游目的地
But with the extremely high running costs, the ISS is still just a destination for the wealthy.
你每天在国际空间站呼吸的空气和吃的东西就要花22,500美元
In order to have food and air during your stay on the ISS, it will cost you $22,500 per day.
加上电力和WiFi之类的杂项
Once everything else like power and wifi is included,
食物&空气供应 $22,500
维生&排泄 $11,250
网络 $50/GB
电力 $42/kWh
在ISS待一宿可能要花至少35,000美元
a one night stay onboard the ISS will cost you at least $35,000.
想要让太空旅行成为现实
In order for space tourism to become a reality,
就得先极大地降低太空居住舱的建造与运营成本
the cost of building and operating a habitat in space will need to be drastically reduced.
太空技术公司“Bigelow航天”就在研发一款大型可充气太空舱
Space Technology startup "Bigelow Aerospace" are developing large inflatable space station modules.
这些舱段可以打包进火箭的载荷舱
These modules can be packed into a rocket's payload bay
并在太空充气后可以变得非常大
and inflated into a much larger size when in space.
他们认为这样的大型可充气舱段是未来太空旅馆的绝佳基础
The idea is that large expandable modules like these could be the perfect foundation for space hotels.
目前 国际空间站需要一大批人24小时工作以保持空间站的运营
Currently, the ISS requires an enormous team of people working 24 hours a day just to keep the station running.
Bigelow航天希望他们能简化舱段的运营流程从而缩减开支
Bigelow Aerospace are hoping to simplify the operation of their modules and reduce the running cost.
并且因为它们制造很容易 发射也比传统的太空舱更便宜
And since they are easier to manufacture and cheaper to launch than traditional space station modules,
所以总的来讲就能降低太空生活的成本
they could reduce the cost of living in space all together.
所以 虽然太空旅行听起来像是遥不可及的科幻
So although the idea of space tourism may seem like a distant fantasy.
但随着太空舱技术与可复用火箭技术的飞速发展
The incredible advancements in reusable rockets and space modules
新一代的太空探索应该很快就会向我们敞开大门
could soon open the door for a brand new generation of explorers.
感谢Brilliant赞助本期Primal Space视频
在网上学习有很多种途径
但Brilliant可以教你理解问题的本质 这就是其独一无二的地方
如果你喜欢本期视频 那你可能会对太空 科学 数学 工程等话题感兴趣
而这些 Brilliant都能满足你
Brilliant是一款带你解决问题的网站 有大量的互动课程
把复杂问题变成无数简单的小问题 让你更加容易理解
Brilliant不会让你死记硬背知识点和公式
而是让你深入理解 让你明白事物的运作原理 并让你能在实际生活中用到它们
如果您想要支持本频道 并且想了解更多关于Brilliant的内容 欢迎前往brilliant.org/primalspace
前200名注册的用户可以获得年费会员的8折优惠
非常感谢大家的观看 我们下期视频见